Reynaldo Bracamonte

Reybrac@yahoo.com

(925) 699-3988

Professional Summary

Energetic leader with a can-do attitude, strategic planning, and willing to be hands on with front-line issues. A proven history in building and leading high-performing teams, coordinating critical initiatives, and introducing process improvement plans that drive results. Experienced in directing operations and service center teams, building new teams/processes from the ground level, and implementing large-scale projects and programs.

Professional Experience

Topcon Positioning Systems

Director of Customer Service

June 2017 to Present

- Leading the management of the company's Global training/ repair certification and customer service departments for positioning systems in a B2B environment to ensure a high-class service delivery to customers
- Responsible for regional service performance for North and South America
- Manage 30+ employees, established and grew team of exempt and hourly employees
- Deployed quality and process improvements and absorbed a 50% increase in work, while reducing headcount and operating costs
- ➤ Lead improvement projects for SalesForce (CRM) and SAP (ERP) working with global teams to deliver a first-class customer experience

Senior Technical Service Manager

April 2011 – June 2017

- Leading the Customer Service department for positioning products
- Reduced equipment repair time from 20+ days to 7 days by automating processes, implementing a structured certification program, and implementing product improvements by collaborating with Quality and Engineering teams
- ➤ Established a New Product Introduction process to improve the release of new products and ensure adequate serviceability in the field

Topcon Medical Laser Systems

Director of Customer Service and Support

June 2017 – February 2020

- ➤ Leading the technical services and support departments for medical devices
- Successfully implemented the ServiceMax CRM and reduced 70% of the manual processes
- > Leading Field Service/Support Engineers (FSE's) to meet a 95% first time resolution rate
- > Ensured adherence to FDA and ISO 13485 regulatory standards
- Built a customer service organization and successfully transitioned to a stand-alone group
- Increased service contract sales by a 200% and achieved a 95% renewal rate

RBracamonte Page 1 of 2

Fresenius Medical Care

Production Supervisor

April 2008 - April 2011

- Managed a medical device manufacturing team
- Responsible for final test and inspection of Hemo Dialysis machines
- Implemented process changes to reduce manufacturing TAT by 20%, resulting in a \$100K cost avoidance per year using Lean Six Sigma methodologies
- Tracked key performance indicators, exceeded weekly/monthly manufacturing goals and ensured adherence to cGMP, FDA, and ISO 13485 regulatory standards

Education

<u>Master of Business Administration (MBA)</u> - DeVry University Keller Graduate School <u>Bachelor of Science (BS) in Electronics Engineering Technology</u> - DeVry University

Skills

- ➤ Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) SAP and MS Dynamics GP
- > Customer Relationship Management systems (CRM) SalesForce and ServiceMax
- > Product Life Cycle Management Arena BOM PLM system and QuadRite's RitePro
- Project/program management, customer success management, continuous process improvement, Budget analysis, change management, metric driven
- Leadership skills, team development, coaching and mentoring, relationship building
- Adaptable, motivated, Strong verbal/written communications skills, conflict resolution
- Bilingual (English & Spanish)
- MS Office suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Technical Skills

- > HTML5, Progressive Web Apps
- CSS3, Bootstrap, and Bulma,
- JavaScript, Express.js, jQuery, Node.js, and React.js
- Database Theory, Agile Methodology
- MongoDB and MySQL
- Command Line and Git

Certificates and Training

UC Davis Coding Boot Camp – May 2021

Global Leadership Development Program -Topcon (Lee Hecht Harrison)

Experienced Manager Boot camp program - UC Berkeley Center for Executive Education

Sustainability process certification - True Market Solutions

Lean Six Sigma Yellow belt - Fresenius Medical Care

Links to sites

https://reybrac.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rey-bracamonte-0595591/

https://github.com/revbrac

RBracamonte Page 2 of 2